ukhairdressers.com 2019-04-12

# Privacy Policy

ukhairdressers is part of UK Webwise.com Limited. This privacy policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you when you visit the ukhairdressers website or when you sign up to receive emails from us.

The privacy of visitors to ukhairdressers is important to us. **We will never sell your personal information to third parties or share your email address with anyone else.**

### 
* What information do we collect from you?

We collect both personal information and anonymous information from you when you visit our website or sign up to receive our marketing newsletters by email. We also collect personal information when you ask an expert a question and when you choose to receive your daily horoscope from us by email. 

Information stored on (or processed by) a computer is called data. "Personal data" means data that allows someone to identify you. This can include your name, email address, postal address and telephone number.

"Anonymous data" is information that is not linked to your personal information and cannot be used to identify you. Anonymous data on how you use our website is collected using cookies.

### 
* How will we use the information we collect?

ukhairdressers uses your personal information to provide you with a customised web experience and to provide services to you. We do not collect or store any more information than is necessary for this.

**Marketing newsletters**

When you register to receive our newsletter emails, ukhairdressers will collect your email address to tell you about new additions to our site. These communications will include notification of the latest hairstyles added to our style gallery, new hair and beauty articles you may be interested in and our current competitions. This information is stored securely on our server. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time by following the link at the bottom of the email.

**Competitions**

When you enter a competition on our site we collect your name, email address and postal address. This is so we can contact you if you win and send you your prize. Additionally, we ask you to tell us your gender and whether or not you have used the brand of products offered as the competition prize. This additional information is used to create anonymous data, to increase our understanding of who is entering our competitions; for example, the proportion of men and women entering. None of these figures are linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

If you win a prize, we will contact you by email to inform you. Your name and postal address will then be shared with the company providing the prize, so that they can send it to you. The winner's name and town of residence are recorded on a list of competition winners which we keep for our records. Once the prizes have been sent out, all other personal information from competition entrants is deleted.

**Horoscopes**

If you sign up to receive your daily horoscope from us, we collect your name, email address and star sign. This information is stored securely on our server. You can unsubscribe from these emails at any time by following the link at the bottom of the email.

**Ask the Experts**

If you choose to submit a question to one of our hair experts, we ask you to provide us with your name and email address. Your personal information is retained until an expert has answered your question. We delete this information after we have contacted you to notify you that the answer is available to view on our website. Your first name is published on the website, alongside your question. If you do not want us to publish your name with your question, you can notify us of this when you submit your question.

**Salon reviews**

If you decide to submit a review of a hair salon you have visited, you need to provide your name and email address. We require your email address to enable us to contact you if we need to clarify any part of your review. If we do not need to clarify anything we will delete your email address when we publish your review. Otherwise your email address will be deleted when we have finished corresponding with you about your review. Your name (usually your first name) is published with your review.

**Style gallery comments**

When you choose to comment on a hairstyle on our website you have the option to include your name. If you do it will be published with your comment. The comments are stored on our secure server and displayed on the website.

**Surveys**

In order to improve our services to our visitors, we may ask you to voluntarily complete confidential surveys. We will not ask you to provide us with any personally identifiable data in association with these surveys. If you do not wish to participate in a survey, however, you can simply decline to participate when asked.

### 
* Do we share your personal information with other companies?

No. We do not sell, trade, rent or share your personal information with third parties.

However, as stated above, we will share some of your personal information with a third party if you are a competition winner, to enable them to send you your competition prize.

### 
* Cookies

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.

ukhairdressers uses cookies to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our sites. For example, we use cookies to create your viewing history in our Style Gallery and to create your own gallery of your favourites styles.

For further information visit _www.aboutcookies.org_ or _www.allaboutcookies.org_.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above websites tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, some of our website features may not function as a result.

### 
* Access to your information and correction

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please write to us at the address in section 9 below. We are legally obliged to ask you to provide us with identification so that we can be certain that you are entitled to receive the requested data.

We are entitled by law to charge a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.

If you decide you want to stop receiving emails from us, you can opt-out at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of one of our emails. If you opt-out we will remove your personal information from our database.

### 
* Where is your information processed and how do we keep it secure?

Your personal data may be processed both in and outside of your own country. We may need to transfer your data outside the UK; however, any company to whom we transfer data is contractually bound to protect your personal data.

ukhairdressers, as part of UK Webwise.com Ltd, is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use, or disclosure. This includes Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology and an industry-standard secured-server. To verify that you have a secure server connection, look for the locked padlock symbol or the https-prefix in the URL.

Except as provided elsewhere in this privacy policy, UK Webwise.com Ltd limits access to personal data in electronic databases to those persons (including employees and contractors) in the organisation who have a business need for such access and those persons are required to keep your data secure.

### 
* Other websites

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website, so when you follow a link to another website you should read their own privacy policies.

When you click on advertisements or links on ukhairdressers, you will leave our site and go to another site. During this process, a third party (including a third party advertising service that may provide services to an advertiser) may collect personal data or anonymous data from you, such as the URL you just came from, the URL you go to next, your browser type, and your IP address. Our display of advertisements or links to any other company or site does not signify our endorsement of such company or site (or the contents of the site). We have no control over, we do not review and our privacy policy does not apply to these other companies, sites, or content, or to any collection of data after you click on an advertisement or link to a third party.

### 
* Changes to our privacy policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review, to ensure we comply with all relevant legislation. We will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 9 May 2018.

### 
* How to contact us

Please contact us if you have any questions about our privacy policy or the information we hold about you. You can do this: 

  * By emailing [_admin@ukhairdressers.com_](mailto:admin@ukhairdressers.com)
  * Or by writing to us at: ukhairdressers.com, UK Webwise.com Ltd, Pelican House, 119c Eastbank Street, Southport, PR8 1DQ
